GNANASEKARAN GAJENDIRAN

SENIOR DEVOPS ENGINEER - Rakuten, Singapore





SUMMARY:

Versatile Senior DevOps Engineer with 10+ years of experience in IT Industry. A CICD guy responsible developing and maintaining CICD frameworks, Transforming legacy apps to modern Kubernetes way. Seeking for changeling environment to apply my Devops expertise and work on modern system/Technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

DevOps Ansible, Kubernetes, Docker, Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, Jira, Jenkins, Maven, Gradle, Nginx, Apache, Vagrant, Rundeck

Prometheus, Elasticsearch, Kibana, Logstash, Filebeat, Metricbeat, SYSDIG, ITRS, SITESCOPE, MONIT **Elk & Monitoring**

Programming Shell Scripting(Advanced), Beginner in (Groovy, Gradle, Python)

OS & RDBMS RedHat, CentOS, Ubuntu & Couchbase, Oracle, MySQL

Certifications Redhat Certified Openshift Administrator. AWS, Elasticsearch and Ansible (Completed Trainings in institutions).

EXPERIENCE:

Rakuten Automated complex legacy apps deployment with zero clicks with Ansible, Jenkins and Bitbucket hook.

Sr Devops Engineer Developed and maintained CICD framework. This framework covering build types gradle, maven, npm **Singapore**

and sbt. Integrated with SonarQube, Jfrog artifactory, ELK and BrowserStack test automation(QA). (Mar2019-Present) Fully Automated CICD platform, Jenkins configurations as code and Pipeline as code with shared lib.

> Note: There is no manual configuration or job creation. Zero code from developers for CICDCT. CICDCT Framework was adopted by 200+ developers. Easy to Scale since Slaves are docker containers. Migrated legacy applications into Kubernetes. Responsible for end to end setup (from code to Live).

Redesigned the existing Prometheus setup and Integrated with Microsoft Teams.

Standard Chartered

Devops Engineer

Chennai

(Jul2014-Feb2019)

Automated Complicated WebMethods Stack Provisioning, slashed 3 days man effort into 2 Hours.

Create and maintain fully automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployment using Jenkins.

Managing 200+ on premise servers by using Ansible, ITRS and Shell Scripting with Uptime 99.9%. Handling huge application volume logs (6 Terra Byte Data) by using Filebeat and Elasticsearch, Which Implemented fully automated Nginx as gateway server, eliminated time killing firewall opening process.

Responsible for High availability of Non-Production Environments. Infosys

Written Monitoring Scripts and Configured in SiteScope to alert services/MQ status. **Technology Analyst**

Chennai

(Mar2013-Jun2014)

Troubleshooting on Network, SAN, DNS, LDAP, DB and OS Levels. Automated many jobs which happened manually.

Implemented Single Click Deployment by using ControlTier. **HCL Technologies**

Automated ControlTier Tool Installation, Configuration and Jobs Creations. Software Engineer

Conducting knowledge transitions cross Support and Dev Teams. Chennai

Worked in Production Support, Automated Batch Process and Monitoring. (Dec2009-Feb2013)

EDUCATION:

BE Anna University

Aug2005 - Jun2009 Electronics and Communications Engineering completed with 75.2%

HSC Tamil Nadu, State Board

Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Biology, Tamil and English completed with 89.3% Jul2002 - May2005

Tamil Nadu, State Board

Mathematics, Science, Social Science, Tamil and English completed with 84.5% Jul2001 - May2002

MORE ABOUT ME:

Received Best performer award (Prepare to succeed) from Rakuten for CICD Framework. Awards &

Promoted as **Devops Engineer (July 2016)** from Standard Chartered Bank. Achievements

Rewarded Best Performer Award (INSTA Award) and Buddy Award from Infosys.

Received multiple appreciations from several US client managers.

Honoured Best Performer Award (Live Wire Award) two times from HCL.

Got centum in 10th mathematics and got 98 marks during 3rd semester mathematics.

HOBBIES DEVOPS, Computer Programming, Sleeping, Surfing on Internet

DOB 21-04-1987 Male Gender

Parent's Name Mr.Gajendiran K, Mrs.Dhanam G

DECLARATION:

I do hereby declare that the above furnished details are true and correct to the best of my knowledge.